Okay, I promised you birds.
1932, the Great Depression.
Farmers in Western Australia are being overrun by
around 20,000 emus eating their props so the
government sends soldiers with machine guns.
The emus scattered, dodged and absorbed bullets.
The operation was pulled back, the press mocked
it and the great emu war became a
legendary defeat.
Emu one, army zero.
Same year the Sydney Harbour Bridge opened and
before the premier could cut the ribbon, a
man named Francis DeGroote galloped in on a
horse and slashed it with a sword.
Peak Australia.
Then the Second World War brought the fight
home.
On the 19th of February, 1942, Japanese aircraft
bombed Darwin.
More bombs were dropped on Darwin than on
Pearl Harbour.
Japanese midget submarines even entered Sydney Harbour.
Australian troops fought through the jungles of the
Kokoda Track in Papua New Guinea to hold
GAC the advance.